Justin Higgins

linkedin.com/in/higginsjustin github.com/higgins

I am a multifaceted engineer with professional experience across the stack. From rapid prototyping to multi-year migrations, I thrive in defining problems, deploying practical solutions and am happy building in green fields or in fields totally overgrown with weeds. Reach out if you'd like to chat!

Work Experience

Staff Software Engineer Soundcloud Aug 2023-Present Web team Los Angeles, CA

- Designed/built an architecture to embed a new web application into a 17 year old one (soundcloud.com) while increasing creator subscription conversions by ~22%
- Redesigned/built artist track upload experience, increasing the perceived total time to upload speed
- Improved lighthouse performance scores across high traffic pages LCP: 88%, FCP: 29%, TTB: 13%
- Established engineering processes for tech debt, code review protocols, ADR proposals, testing standards for our international engineering team
- Added Rive animations and leveled up our design team to utilize the new format, tactically animating static assets
- Led the Summer Engineering Internship program '24, '25

Head of Engineering Turntable.fm 2021-2023

Core product

- Remote
- Design/built backend services for real-time video streaming, audio messaging and video messaging apps
- Design/built payment and reward service for influencers promoting our services

Launched 4 consumer web and mobile products under my engineering leadership

• Products: Glow.dev, Sup.audio, Seen.lol, Hightide.link

Staff Software Engineer Hustle 2017-2021

Web, Mobile, API

San Francisco, CA, USA | Remote

- Doubled perceived performance of client message sending speed
- Designed/built new message "targeting" system allowing clients to reference full history of their platform usage for subsequent use
- Migrated entire codebase off Parse SDK and onto GraphQL gateway

Founder Selfless 2015-2020

San Francisco, CA

- Designed/built/launched web and mobile service for sharing physical goods with friends and neighbors
- Solo marketed to communities in the Bay Area

Senior Software Engineer 2012-2015 Apple

Beats Music, Core API

San Francisco, CA | Cupertino, CA USA

- Designed/built billing system responsible for subscription revenue through an ancient payment gateway
- Built internal content scheduler for editorial team

Education and Certifications

• **B.A. Physics** University of California, Berkeley.

2007-2011

B.A. Astrophysics University of California, Berkeley.

Technologies and Languages

• Languages: Typescript, Javascript, Node.js, Python, Elisp, Ruby, Go

Technologies: React, React-Native, GraphQL, Next, MySQL, PostgresQL, AWS, Terraform, Git
Other: Cloudflare, AWS, Drizzle, HonoJS, Rive, Elasticsearch, Redis, Cassandra, Firebase

Projects

- 24HourHomepage.com An internet art project earning ProductHunt's #2 product of the day
- MagicButton.club A passion project promoting indie musicians
- <u>Privatize</u> (git plugin) An open source tool for transparently encrypting HEREDOCs in a git repository
- Everyone Everywhere All At Once An internet art project inspired by the Oscar winning film Everything Everywhere All At Once
- <u>GitPushups.com</u> A fitness tool and community for developers to block their code if they don't do pushups

Interests

- I love camping with my wife and dog and exploring Mexico
- I run an annual goals motivation club for people's New Year's resolutions
- I am a film buff and keep a huge collection of DVDs and Blu ray worth owning